So, I listened to the creator of Claude
Code explain why Claude has gotten worse
and how to actually fix that. And I
learned something that sounds really
weird, but more skills and more system
prompts are probably breaking your
system. So, I dug deeper into this and I
started doing some testing and I found
that there are three super important
things that everyone has to be doing
right now. It's super easy to do and you
don't need any technical experience to
actually implement this stuff. So, I
don't want to waste any time. Let's just
get straight to the video. So, let's
just start off with some real quick
context on what they're actually doing
behind the scenes at Anthropic.
>> Let's talk a bit about the new release.
You actually deleted over 80% of the
system prompt from Claude Code.
>> Yes.
>> Tell us more about that.
>> I think something that a lot of people
might not realize is um
Claude Code as a product and as a
harness is just always changing. We're
always adding stuff. We're always
deleting stuff.
Every time that a new model comes out,
we delete a bunch of the system prompt,
change a bunch of the system prompt, we
change the set of tools all the time, we
change the prompts for the tools all the
time. And the reason is
every model is very different.
So, something that you did for one model
maybe 3 months ago, it just might not
translate at all to the next model.
And so, one thing about Opus 5 is it's
just really intelligent. And a lot of
the stuff in the system prompt was
correcting for these behaviors that the
model should have known,
but uh it didn't.
Now, Opus 5 just does it.
>> So, that's interesting. It makes you
think a little bit, but I just wanted to
sort of lay the foundation of they're
doing that at Anthropic. They are
treating each different model as like a
different completely different
personality, different flaws, different
strengths, and different ways that you
should prompt it. And so, whenever a new
model drops, one of the things that I
tell you guys is like, "Hey, run you
this model through your skills. Make
sure they all still work. Make sure they
all still feel good." And for some
reason with Opus 5, it's just felt
degraded to the point where I'm actually
going back to 4.8 every once in a while
when I need to do something and I'm just
getting better results. But, I never
really thought about, "Hmm, maybe if I
just got rid of some of my instructions
and got out of the model's way, it is
actually just more intelligent now and
it could handle those things." So, take
a look at this next clip.
>> Yeah, and and for people that aren't
building agentic products, but you're
using Claude code, every 6 months delete
your Claude MD.
Delete your skills.
Delete your hooks.
See what the model does and it might
surprise you.
And actually for Opus 5, this is
something we really do recommend is just
try deleting all of these things
because the model might really just not
need all those instructions that you
needed for past models.
>> So, when you think about that for a sec,
I feel like that almost sounds
counterintuitive because what we've been
told is, "Hey, you know, if everyone has
access to the same model," or something
this is something I say a lot, "then
wouldn't everybody be getting the same
results?" And to an extent that is very
true. But, if Boris is basically saying,
"Hey, remove your skills, remove your
own system prompts and just see what's
possible," it's a different way to think
about it because the the the immediate
thing that I think about is like, "Okay,
let's say that I was teaching um a
10-year-old, a college student, and
someone that's been in the workforce for
10 years how to do something, how to do
something like create a slide deck. I
would probably give the 10-year-old the
most specific instructions. I would say,
"Hey, here's exactly what you should be
looking for. Here are the 10 slides to
make. Here's what the title should look
like. Here's the color. Here's the way
that the text should be formatted." I
would be super specific and I basically
wouldn't give that 10-year-old any
freedom really to just kind of go
experiment because if it's a high-stakes
thing, we want to just steer it. But, as
you work your way up the chain in, I
guess, like intelligence and experience,
what if you gave that same instruction
set to the person who's been working for
10 years and has made hundreds of slide
decks? You're going to get in their way.
They're not going to be able to actually
use their subject matter expertise and
their intelligence to put their own spin
on it. And so, I'm not saying that it's
always the case, but I think that there
is an element of like removing some of
the some of the like kind of
instructions and constraints on a model.
They call this unhobbling the model,
which I'll play a clip from in just a
minute here. But, take a look at this
example I ran. So, after I watched this
interview, I made a duplicate of my repo
and I took away the Claude MD and I took
away all my skills and I just started
using it a little bit to see how it
worked and it was okay but what my gut
is telling me about that is when we're
doing something like we have you know an
AI operating system and we have the
Claude MD which is kind of routing
around to hey here is Nate's business
context here are where all these files
live here where the wikis live that's
important we still need that context of
hey Mr. Claude code here's where you
find your things but when it comes to
actual tasks maybe you just get out of
the way a little bit and that's where
your skills aren't as important or your
skills are changed and so what I mean by
this is take a look. Here is an output I
ran where I took this YouTube video this
interview that we're watching I gave
that URL to Claude and say hey make me a
YouTube resource guide like the resource
guides that I make for you guys when I
have other videos and so what this did
is it broke it down right it created a
nine page resource guide it's formatted
nicely it has like these colors it has
like these little blocks and it has my
also like my header right it's got that
header image it's got my YouTube channel
links right here at the bottom it links
to AI S Plus. So those are things that
are like very specific so those are
things that it's like my preferences and
my styles. Now look at this version this
is one on a fresh session where I gave
it basically the same prompt but it had
no skills or no context to work from and
here's what it created obviously it
doesn't look as good right it just looks
a bit messier it doesn't have nice
formatting there's no header but
I think that this is a better output
because I didn't tell it specifically
hey for a resource guide do this this
and this here's how you break it down.
This actually broke this down into ideas
which I thought was really nice and each
idea has a timestamp. So here we have
prompts are disposable here we have
rebuild from observation all of these
main ideas that it covers we have
timestamps so arguably I like the
content of this version better which had
no skills no Claude MD but what I would
do is I would bake this into a skill and
say hey by the way make the resource
guide however you want however you see
fit but what I want you to do is take
this image and put it in the header and
link to my YouTube channel at the top
and link to AI S Plus at the bottom. So
those are the areas where I think it's
less in my mind about deleting all your
skills, it's more about really thinking
about them, and maybe making versions of
them that aren't as specific. And real
quick, as I'm editing this video,
there's one other thing I wanted to
throw out there that I think is super
important to think about, which is you
can't just take advice you see from
Boris Cherney or from some other
YouTuber or from me or from someone in
the community and just
blanket statement apply it to your work.
It just doesn't work like that. Because
what my gut's telling me is a lot of
this advice that Boris is going to tell
you, or that you might see Andrej
Karpathy tweet about, a lot of their
advice is coming from the perspective of
someone who's like in the weeds
designing harnesses, working on massive
code bases every day,
training models. That's not what I do. I
don't know if that's what you do or not,
but you should probably be taking advice
from people who are using the AI systems
the same way you want to. For me, that's
generally bunch of research, knowledge
work, um creating documents, creating
deliverables, but not as much like
building software. That's not what I'm
doing on the day-to-day. So, I just
wanted to throw that out there. I think
that Boris has some really good advice
here, but the reason why I didn't
actually go out and sweep delete all of
my stuff is because based on my findings
and my testings, that wouldn't be as
valuable to me as just kind of like
reworking them. I think people that are
building products and software have like
these all of these skills to like build
and to orchestrate, and maybe that's
where those skills should be completely
deleted because the model and the
harness just does that better now. But
as you saw from this demo, like I still
need the skills to say, "Hey, you're
going to grab this image. You're going
to put that there. Um you're going to
use these color schemes cuz that's like
our brand guidelines." That sort of
stuff is still important context for my
systems, for my knowledge work. So, just
something important to keep in mind. And
Boris seems to completely agree. Let me
show you guys this next clip.
>> Yeah, so hobbling is this idea in a
research that the model is doing
something and you're just getting in the
way.
There There's this kind of like way of
thinking about it that I really like.
It's very useful when you're building
product. And um it it it's called
product overhang.
And the the idea is
the model is able to do all sorts of
things
with today's models, not a future model,
but today's model, that we have not yet
realized.
And there are so many capabilities the
model has like this that people are not
aware of. So, there's a couple things
that I will think about. One is
you should give the model slightly
harder tasks than what you think it can
do.
I think a a really common mistake that I
see is people are using Claude code,
they're using Claude, and they they just
give it like way overly specific
instructions. They're like, I want you
to do this, but I want you to do it in
this way, this way, this way. You must
do like one, then two, then three, then
four.
And for modern models, that's actually
really not the way to do it. You want to
go a little bit higher level.
You want to describe the task, you want
to describe the guardrails, you want to
describe like the exit criteria, and
then just go with the model cook,
and come back in a little bit.
And I think it'll it'll surprise you.
Like, and again, like this is just not
something that would have worked 6
months ago, but it does work today.
>> So, if you weren't convinced when I said
that earlier, hopefully you're convinced
now that you've heard Boris Cherny say
that. And I think that there's so many
things that go into this, right? There's
obviously the balance of using your
Claude at MD in a way that doesn't
hobble the model. Same thing with your
skills. And then there's also the
balance of actually getting an output
that you like, because I think a lot of
us get frustrated when we ask Claude to
do something, it comes back, and the
output's just very mediocre. But maybe
that was on you. Maybe it was your job
to say, "Hey, here is what good looks
like." Because if it doesn't know what
good looks like, how does it actually
create something that's good? So, like
Boris said, you give it a high-level
goal, you set the standard, and say
basically, "Don't stop until you're
done, until you've hit the standard."
So, when you think of setting a slash
goal when you're using these AI agents,
you're not just saying, "Hey, here's
what good looks like." You're also
saying, "Here are X, Y, and Z things
that you do in order to prove that this
has been reached." And you keep
iterating on that until you've actually
proven it. You verify yourself so that I
don't have to verify. For example,
something that I've been throwing at the
end of my slash goals after I've given
it all the standards and the
verification methods, I basically say
like, "I'm not looking for a prototype
or proof-of-concept. I'm looking for you
to give me something that has been
tested and iterated on 10 times and has
been fully QA'd and that's ready to go
to market tomorrow." That makes it a
little bit more emotional. And sometimes
when I prompt things with emotion, seems
to do better. But let's take a look at
what Boris said about verification.
>> I I think the skill nowadays
is less about prompt engineering and
more about figuring out how do you give
Claude a hard task
that seems a little bit too hard.
And then how do you make it possible for
Claude to verify its work along the way?
And the verification, I think, is
probably the single most important thing
that people do not get right virtually.
>> It's really, really interesting to see
how the creator of Claude code is
thinking about this because the more
that I get into the space and the more
that I talk to people that are starting
to get into the space,
the more I realize that
the skills that are transferring over
here, it obviously doesn't matter.
They're tool agnostic. If you want to
use Claude code, Hermes, Agent Cortex,
whatever it is. The tools that are the
skills that really are important is
managing AI agents. And when I say
managing, I mean a similar way to when
you manage people. Now, I haven't been
managing people for very long, right?
But what I do know is that good managers
don't just
micromanage, right? They're not saying,
"This is what you should do. This is how
you do it. Go do it." They get out of
their people's way. They check in with
them. They review. They have judgment.
They have taste. But they also let those
people use their brains. Like they were
hired for a reason. And so essentially,
you should be thinking about all these
agents and all these sessions that
you're spinning up, you're using them
for a reason. Outsource the thinking to
them. Let them think and let them come
up with ideas, but give them an ability
to have other agents play devil's
advocate. Give them an ability to check
their own work and verify. Outsource
some of the thinking, but never
outsource the understanding. At the end
of the day, you're still like the
founder of these agents and you are
driving the vision, but they're able to
help you so much. So So I could talk
about this all day. I think that this is
super interesting. If you guys want to
check out this interview, it was like a
35-minute interview on the Y Combinator
YouTube channel. I will leave a link to
it in the description as well. These
were just some of the key highlights
that I wanted to pull out and break
down. And let me know if you guys enjoy
this type of video, if you enjoy this
type of breakdown. And hopefully you
found it valuable, you learned something
new, and there's something that you want
to try. If you did, please give it a
like, it helps me out a ton. And as
always, I appreciate you guys making it
to the end of the video.
And I'll see you on the next one.